Somme Sakounthong

Freelance UX Design / Front-end Dev Consultant

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/ssakounthong

Website: www.dragondrop.co Email: info@dragondrop.co

SUMMARY

I bridge the gap between visual designers, developers and business analysts. My involvement through the entire cycle of a project enables the projects end result to be a rounded balance of user needs and business goals.

With the combination of a strong creative background, attention to detail, along with my extensive experience and technical skills I can deliver on projects from the initial briefing right through to build, testing and completion with successful results on time and in budget.

Being in the digital industry since 2000 I've developed a passion for digital, an eye for detail and appreciation for simplicity. My experience has given me exposure to different working environments and capabilities so I'm able to connect with people at all levels.

KEY SKILLS

- Rapid prototyping experience using a wide range of tools and methods such as: paper and pencil, Bootstrap, Photoshop, Illustrator, Axure, OmniGRaffle and Balsamic
- Ability to hand-code compliant web standard HTML5, CSS, SASS, jQuery and JavaScript
- Experience with server side technologies such as Node.js, Grunt, Mustache, Express, PHP and Scala
- Basic knowledge of JavaScript frameworks such as Angular and Backbone.
- Experience in developing single page and large scale apps
- Experience in cross browser development ie6 and up
- Experience with testing suites such as Jasmine and Cucumber
- Experience with terminal commands and version control such as Git
- Experience in developing custom Wordpress sites and plugins
- Understanding of responsive, adaptive and mobile technologies
- Experience in developing to WCAG 2.0 accessibility guidelines
- Advocate of Agile, Scrum and Kanban methodologies
- Ability to pick up new tools and technologies
- Experience in working with multidisciplinary teams and collaboration with designers, researchers, developers, business analysts, testers and key stakeholders
- A keen eye for visual design and an understanding of the importance of use needs and business goals



RELEVANT WORK HISTORY

Senior UX Designer/Front-end Developer, Kainos (London -

England) February 2013 – March 2015

- Lead overall front-end development and design for solutions that are fit for purpose
- Requirements capture, storyboarding, high fidelity prototyping, visual design and user testing
- Liaise with graphic designers, developers, testers, project owners and stakeholders as required
- Deliver pragmatic solutions within the commercial constraints that apply to the project
- Mentoring less experienced team members and leading by example in both technical and non-technical aspects
- Work as part of a multi-disciplined agile team to design/develop user focussed and successful services
- Adhere to branding guidelines and deliver designs that meet W3C standards
- Deliver iterative design components (including user journeys) based on user feedback
- Build relationships and work effectively with clients and suppliers

UX Developer, Reading Room (London - England) December 2012 – February 2013 (contract)

- Front-end development of websites and Internet based applications
- Work across projects with a team of designers and developers to create high quality websites
- Develop HTML5, JQuery and CSS3 front ends that integrate with CMS based platforms
- Maintain active knowledge of and implement best practices.
- Hand code working prototypes from scamps and wireframes
- Cross-browser debugging in an efficient and structured approach
- Attend client meetings and answer any technical queries
- Follow functional specs and adhere to brand guidelines

International Designer/Developer, CBS Interactive (London - England) October 2009 – July 2012

- Front-end design and development of any new requirements or enhancements of the International email delivery, email management and reporting systems
- Design, development and maintenance of the TechLibrary iPhone/iPad App
- Product development
- Project manage international design and development projects
- Ensure projects are delivered on time
- Create functional specs and liaise with back end development team in Singapore
- Ensure best practices and thought leadership of the international interactive team
- Prototype ideas, storyboarding and wireframes
- Attend client meetings with sales and answer any technical queries
- Ensure the best UX (User Experience) for all projects
- Ownership of UX testing and focus groups
- Integrate social integration across lead generation campaigns
- The go-to-guy for anything interactive



Campaign Manager, CBS Interactive (London - England)

November 2007 - October 2009

- Working with the sales team to understand client needs
- Create campaign plans & schedules to achieve campaign objectives
- Manage all aspects of campaign set up and ongoing campaign execution
- Email broadcasting using an email delivery system
- Develop detailed post campaign reports and provide recommendations on how to improve results
- Delivering campaigns on time within budget.
- Interactive thought leadership, ensuring interactive best practice
- Ensure CBS Interactive exceeds client expectations and over delivers on the overall campaign proposal
- Design develop html email creatives, registration pages and other interactive products such as micro-sites and e-books, e-games

Interactive Designer, Marie Curie Cancer Care (London - England)

June 2006 - November 2007

- Design and development of interactive flash projects, microsites and landing pages
- Creation of web graphics, banners, and image optimization
- Design, development and maintenance of MCCC online shopping site
- Liaise with external agencies and internal departments

GUI Designer, Envisional (Cambridge, England)

May 2006 (contract)

- Redesign the GUI (Graphical User Interface) of their existing web application
- Liaise with the development and marketing team
- Actively participate in brainstorming sessions providing useful input on UI issues
- Construct Photoshop, static HTML mock-ups and provide graphics

Graphic Designer, Urban Capital (Dublin, Ireland)

December 2005 (contract)

- Redesign of corporate identity and collateral
- Demonstrate the high quality of Urban Capita's work
- Support entry into new Eastern European markets
- Reduce the time it takes to prepare tenders

Graphic Designer, Pioneer Investments (Dublin, Ireland)

September 2005 (contract)

- Typesetting, completing layouts and producing graphics using InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator
- Preparing finished artwork for print
- Actively participating in brainstorming and briefing sessions
- Finding effective creative solutions to complex design problems whilst using existing brand guidelines.



Graphic Designer, Dublin Theatre Festival (Dublin, Ireland)

June 2005 (contract)

• The design and layout of show programs, posters, advertisements and promotional material using InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator.

CBS Interactive (Sydney, Australia)

Senior Designer from March 2003 - February 2005 Designer from December 2000 - March 2003

- Training, mentoring and management of design team
- Responsible for the front-end design, maintenance, development and testing of zdnet.com.au, builderau.com.au, cnet.com.au, technonogyandbusiness.
- Integration of third-party services into company Web sites and online campaigns
- Offer input and innovation in terms of out of the box sales programs
- Responsible for the photography in C-level magazine and Government titles each month
- Creation of images and Flash animation/action scripting for ads and Web site
- Responsible for the design, layout and covers of Builder Magazine
- Assist the print designer with image/illustration creation and magazine layout as needed
- Film, edit and maintain CNET streaming videos
- Design and development of new HTML and text newsletters
- Continually assist the sales team on advanced creative requests when needed
- Design, development and maintenance of the current and new Power Centres and Microsites
- Design and development of all Announce newsletters, including: Salesrelated, co-branded and internal
- Design and development of all online rich media for the online and print divisions

Web designer, Macquarie University (Sydney, Australia)

August 2000 - December 2000

- Front-end design of online learning websites for various subjects in Macquarie University
- Liaising with the different departments/clients during each design project from start to finish

EDUCATION

- 2003: Photography short course, Australian Centre of Photography NSW
- 1997 2000: Advance Diploma of Graphic Design, Hornsby TAFE Centre of Technology - Australia
- 1990 1996: High School Certificate, St Johns Park High Australia

VISA STATUS

Indefinite leave to remain (full residency and right to work in the UK)

SECURITY CLEARANCE

SC Level (valid till 2020)

